Giulio Ammendola

Interaction Designer

Giulio Ammendola

7/2/1989, Firenze

25 Vyner Street E2 9DG London, UK

+44(0)7940069555 giulio.ammendola@gmail.com

Profile

I am an Interaction Designer working at the intersection of the physical and digital, and specifically interested in challenging how we interact with technology to create a better world that everyone can use and understand. I craft playful interactive experiences and experimental interfaces employing my skills in electronics, product development and design. I hold dual British and Italian nationality.

Experience

Self Employed / Interaction Designer

APRIL 2021 - PRESENT, LONDON

After having gained experience in both the corporate and startup environments, I started my own studio to collaborate with a range of large and small clients delivering across design, prototyping and product development. Most recently I was awarded a IF award award in the UX Category for my project Teenage Firefighting - designing and building an interactive experience for children.

John Lewis / Lead Interaction Designer

FEB 2019 - APRIL 2021, LONDON

As part of Room Y (the John Lewis and Waitrose innovation lab), I design interactive products, services, and experiences. I worked across media using Unreal Engine, iOS and web on a range of challenging future facing projects to enhance the partnership portfolio.

SAM Labs / Product Owner, Hardware

JAN 2017 - AUG 2018, LONDON

Managing a range of products for their entire life cycle (from ideation through development, manufacturing, launch, and improvement), I helped develop and deliver a product vision and roadmap for a new range of wireless building blocks for kids to learn coding.

SAM Labs / Product Designer

JUNE 2014 - DEC 2016, LONDON

Having joined the newly born company to produce the opening Kickstarter campaign, I then worked on many different aspects of the company; my role changed and adapted over time to include brand strategy, UX, product and interaction design.

Education

RCA & Imperial College / MA-MSc Innovation Design Engineering SEPT 2013 - JULY 2015, LONDON

I achieved a distinction in the two years double Master's programme across the Royal College of Art and Imperial College London. Main tutors: Durrell Bishop, Miles Pennington.

London College of Communication / BA Sound Arts and Design

SEPT 2009 - JUNE 2012, LONDON

I achieved a First Class Honors degree at London College of Communication, University of the Arts, London.

Liceo Classico Michelangelo / High School Diploma

SEPT 2004 - JUNE 2009, FIRENZE (ITALY)

I graduated from High School with 78/100.

Skills

Interaction design, product design and development, with a focus on the bridge between physical and digital. I have experience in manufacturing, user testing and product delivery.

Italian: mother tongue

English: fluent

Product Design: Rhinoceros, Fusion 360, Keyshot UX/UI: Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch, Illustrator, Photoshop

Prototyping: Arduino, Processing

Coding: SwiftUI, Javascript, and basic C++

Sound: Ableton Live, MAX/MSP